Guide to the Confederate Imprint collection, 1855-1879 MS 071
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Confederate Imprint collection
1855-1879
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Confederate States of America.
MS 071
16 Linear Feet
Official documents, books, advertisements, religious pamphlets, maps, and various other materials related to life in the Confederacy during the period of the U.S. Civil War.
Biographical Note
Dr. Samuel A. Greene is largely responsible for amassing this collection during his tenure as librarian of the Massachusetts Historical Society. He was a Civil War veteran, and held his post with the Society from the end of the Civil War until World War I.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 16 boxes of books and papers, mostly from the 1860s, all of which were readily available to the public in the Confederacy at the time. The collection includes state and C.S.A. laws, ordinances, and regulations, military manuals, political dissertations, school books, novels, maps, tracts, and sermons. Also included are works related to the Confederacy such as histories of the war and autobiographies. Most are originals, any photocopies are noted as such in this listing.
The numbers associated with most items refers to numbers used in the published volumes of citations "Confederate Imprints: A checklist based principally on the collection of the Boston Athenaeum", by Marjorie Lyle Crandall, published in two volumes by the Boston Atheneaum, 1955 and in "More Confederate Imprints", by Richard Harwell, The Virginia State Library, 1957.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Purchased 1964.
Arrangement
This materials has been arranged in number order according to the numbering scheme in "Confederate Imprints: A checklist based principally on the collection of the Boston Athenaeum", by Marjorie Lyle Crandall, published in two volumes by the Boston Atheneaum, 1955 and in "More Confederate Imprints", by Richard Harwell, The Virginia State Library, 1957.
Missing Title
Series I: S Numbers, 1859-1864
Series II: Harwell Numbers; 1860-1865
Series III: Crandall Numbers; 1855-1867
Series X: Oversize
General
Many of these original imprints can be found on microfilm:
"Confederate imprints, 1861-1865" microform Crandall, Marjorie Lyle, 1900- Confederate imprints. Title: Confederate imprints, 1861-1865 microform Publication info: New Haven, Conn.: Research Publications, [1974]. Physical description: 144 microfilm reels; 35 mm. General note: Based on: "Confederate imprints" / Marjorie Lyle Crandall. Boston: Boston Athenaeum, 1955. "More Confederate imprints" / Richard B. Harwell. Richmond: Virginia State Library, 1957. General note: Reproduces text of titles listed in Crandall and Harwell bibliographies arranged by bibliography number. Fondren Library call # E487 .C73 1974.
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865)
Document Types
imprints (publication statements); Maps; government records; pamphlets; sermons; military records; novels; broadsides (notices)
Places
Confederate States of America; United States
Subjects (Corporations)
Confederate States of America.
- Series I: S Numbers, 1859-1864, 228559
  - U.S. Army. Army of Virginia General Orders. Nos. 1-20 (lacking 14), June 27-August 15, 1862; 228743 (Box 1, Folder S1)
  - US Army. Department of Ohio. General Orders. Nos. 1-55, January 5-April 30, 1863; 228742 (Box 1, Folder S2.1)
  - US Army. Department of the Ohio General Orders. Nos. 56-110, May 2-June 29 1863; 228741 (Box 1, Folder S2.2)
  - US Army. Department of the South. Circular Nos. 1-5, January 4-May 27, 1865; 228740 (Box 1, Folder S3)
  - US Army. Department of the South. General Orders. Nos. 1-55 (lacking 19), Jan.2- May 3, 1865; 228739 (Box 1, Folder S4.1)
  - US Army. Department of the South. General Orders. Nos. 56-112, May 5-July 17, 1865; 228738 (Box 1, Folder S4.2)
  - US Army. Department of the South. General Orders Index, 1865; 228737 (Box 1, Folder S4.3)
  - Illinois Governor (Yates). Governor's Message 8p, April 23, 1861; 228736 (Box 1, Folder S5)
  - Iowa. Governor (Kirkwood). Special Message Delivered to Iowa General Assembly in extra session, September 3, 1862; 228735 (Box 1, Folder S6)
  - Maryland. General Assembly. Report of the Committee on Federal Relations in regard to the calling of a sovereign convention. 22p., May 9, 1861; 228734 (Box 1, Folder S7)
  - Wisconsin. Laws and Statutes. Laws of Wisconsin and of the US, in relation to the militia in actual service. 45 p., 1861; 228733 (Box 1, Folder S8)
  - Confederate States of America. President. Message of the President. 4p., September 24, 1862; 228732 (Box 1, Folder S9)
  - Confederate States of America, Programme for the Inauguration of the President (photography), 1862; 228731 (Box 1, Folder S9a)
  - Confederate States of America. Army of the Potomac. Medical Director's Office. General Orders no. 9, October 3, 1861; 228730 (Box 1, Folder S10)
  - Confederate States of America. Army of the Potomac. General Orders No. 76, December 8, 1861; 228729 (Box 1, Folder S11)
  - Post Office Regulations, 1862; 228728 (Box 1, Folder S12a)
  - Confederate States of America. Surgeon-General's Office. Broadside, September 30, 1861; 228727 (Box 1, Folder S13)
  - Confederate States of America. Treasury Dept. Blank Check of the Treasurer of the Confederate States. Richmond, 186-; 228726 (Box 1, Folder S14)
  - Confederate States of America. Department of State. Form Letter. 1p., 1861; 228725 (Box 1, Folder S12)
  - Confederate States of America. Treasury Dept. Blank Promissory Note by the Treasurer of the Confederate States., 186-; 228724 (Box 1, Folder S15)
  - Confederate States of America. Treasury Dept. Regulations in Relation to Payment of Interest on the Public Debt. Broadside, 186-; 228723 (Box 1, Folder S16)
  - Confederate States of America. War Dept. Report of Secretary of War. 18p., November 3, 1864; 228722 (Box 1, Folder S17)
  - Confederate States of America. War Dept. Ordnance Office and Circular Letter 1, 1861; 228721 (Box 1, Folder S17a)
  - Mississippi Valley Union. Convention Report. 5p., September 12, 1864; 228720 (Box 1, Folder S18)
  - Georgia General Assembly. Resolutions expressive of the Determination of Georgia to Prosecute the Present War with the Utmost Energy and Vigor 2p., November 24, 1863; 228719 (Box 1, Folder S19)
  - New Orleans. Mayor. Blank Form For a Pass For a Slave, 1862; 228718 (Box 1, Folder S20)
  - Missouri. General Assembly. An Act to Provide for the Organization, Government, and Support of the Military Forces of the State of Missouri. 43p., 1861; 228717 (Box 1, Folder S21)
  - North Carolina. Enlistment Papers for the "State Troops of North Carolina" 4p., 186-; 228716 (Box 1, Folder S22)
  - Texas. Adjutant General. Circular, no. 34, 1863; 228715 (Box 1, Folder S23a)
  - Tennessee. Governor (Isham). Message of His Excellency, Isham G. Harris, to the General Assembly 24p., January 7, 1861; 228714 (Box 1, Folder S23)
  - Virginia Convention. Circular Letter 1p., 1861; 228713 (Box 1, Folder S24)
  - Pardigon, C. F. The Practice of War 216p. (only the back cover remains), 1863; 228712 (Box 1, Folder S25)
  - Clark, Peter H. The Black Brigade of Cincinnati 30p., 1864; 228711 (Box 1, Folder S26)
  - Cutter, O. P. Our Battery, or the Journey of Company B, 1st O.V.A. (1st Ohio Artillery) 152p., 1864; 228710 (Box 1, Folder S27)
  - Independent Burnet Rifles Battalion. Constitution and By-Laws 20p., 1861; 228709 (Box 1, Folder S28)
  - Love, John. Report of Mayor-General Love, of the Indiana Legion. 13p. (with this is bound "Reports of Brigade and Regimental Officers, Indiana Legion", p17-72.), 1863; 228708 (Box 1, Folder S29)
  - Proceedings of the officers and Soldiers of the Indiana Regiments in the Army of the Cumberland. 93 p., 1863; 228707 (Box 1, Folder S30)
  - Resolutions of Thanks to Mayor-General Rosecrans, with Gen. Rosecrans' Reply; And the Address of the Ohio Soldiers to the People of Ohio; together with the correspondence connected therewith. 8p., 1863; 228706 (Box 1, Folder S31)
  - Fanning, Thomas W. The Adventures of a Volunteer, By a Non-Commissioned Officer 94p., 1863; 228705 (Box 1, Folder S32)
  - A Full Account of the Capture and Wonderful Escape of Gen. John H. Morgan with Capt. T. Henry Hines 16p., 1864; 228704 (Box 1, Folder S33)
  - Funeral Services at the Burial of the Right Rev. Leonidas Polk, DD 28p., June 29, 1864; 228703 (Box 1, Folder S34)
  - Gen. McClellan's Record. His Sympathy with the South 12p., 1864; 228702 (Box 1, Folder S35)
  - Hallock, Charles. Sketches of "Stone Wall" Jackson 56p., 1863; 228701 (Box 1, Folder S36)
  - Hurlbut, Henry Higgins. "A Paper Read at a Family Meeting of Some of Samuel Hurlbut's Descendants", 22p. (includes family tree), September 20, 1860; 228700 (Box 1, Folder S37)
  - Ohio Boys in Dixie. The Adventures of 22 Scouts Sent By Gen. O.M. Mitchell to Destroy a Railroad 47p., 1863; 228699 (Box 1, Folder S38)
  - Stagg, Abraham. Biographical Sketches of the Fifty-Sixth Ohio Senate 75p., January 4, 1864; 228698 (Box 1, Folder S39)
  - Wilkes, George. McClellan: From Ball's Bluff to Antietam 40p., 1863; 228697 (Box 1, Folder S40)
  - Wright, Joseph A. "Eulogy on Stephen A. Douglas" 16p., January 8, 1862; 228696 (Box 1, Folder S41)
  - "An Appeal to the Democracy of Indiana; Resolutions of 66th, 93d and 34th Indiana Regiments"; Speech of Alexander H. Stephens 8p., 1863; 228695 (Box 1, Folder S42)
  - Arizona Historical Society. Charter, Constitution and By-Laws of the Arizona Historical Society 16p., November 1864; 228694 (Box 1, Folder S43)
  - Betts, Samuel R. The Blockade. The Cases of the Hiawatha and Other Vessels Captured as Prize 25p., 1861; 228693 (Box 1, Folder S44)
  - Bonaparte, Jerome-Napoleon. Cour Imperiale de Paris. Premiere Chambre. Appel de Jugement de la Premiere Chambre de Tribunal de Premiere Instance de la Seine 13p., February 14, 1861; 228692 (Box 1, Folder S45)
  - Carrey, Emile. Grandeur et Avenir des Etats-Unis 48p., 1863; 228691 (Box 1, Folder S46)
  - Cleveland as a Naval Depot. Report of a Committee of Citizens. 8p. (map), 1864; 228690 (Box 1, Folder S47)
  - First Anniversary of the Proclamation of Freedom in South Carolina 17p., January 1, 1864; 228689 (Box 1, Folder S48)
  - The Great Panic: Being Incidents Connected with Two Weeks of the War in Tennessee 36p., 1862; 228688 (Box 1, Folder S49)
  - The Great Slave Holders' Rebellion 8p., 186-; 228687 (Box 1, Folder S50)
  - The Great Union Meeting (at Indianapolis) 16p., February 26, 1863; 228686 (Box 1, Folder S51)
  - Laugel, Auguste. Les Causes et Caracteres de la Guerre Civile aux Etats-Unis 24p., November 1861; 228685 (Box 1, Folder S52)
  - A Letter to an English Friend on the American War 24p., 1863; 228684 (Box 1, Folder S53)
  - Morrison, Marion. A History of the Ninth Regiment, Illinois Volunteer Infantry 95p., 1864; 228683 (Box 1, Folder S54)
  - Murphy, D.F. The Jeff Davis Piracy Cases. Full Report of the Trial of William Smith for Piracy, as One of the Crew of the Confederate Privateer, the Jeff Davis. 100p., October 1861; 228682 (Box 1, Folder S55)
  - National Armory. An Appeal to Congress by the Citizens of Rock Island and Moling, Illinois, and Davenport, Iowa, in favor of a National Armory on the site of Fort Armstrong, on the Island of Rock Island, in the State of Illinois. 14p. (appendix and map), 1861; 228681 (Box 1, Folder S56)
  - Philadelphia. Union League letters from General Rosecrans to the Democracy of Indiana 8p., 1863; 228680 (Box 1, Folder S57)
  - The Soldier of Indiana in the War for the Union 142p., 1864; 228679 (Box 1, Folder S58)
  - Our Cruise in the Confederate States' War Steamer Alabama. The Private Journal of an Officer 64p., September 19, 1863; 228678 (Box 1, Folder S59)
  - Address by the Loyal Democracy of Wisconsin to the People of the State 13p., September 17, 1863; 228677 (Box 1, Folder S60)
  - Address of the Merchants of the City of Norfolk, VA to Brigadier-General Henry M. Naglee and his reply 8p., October 1863; 228676 (Box 1, Folder S61)
  - Address of the Union Members of the (Indiana) legislature 15p., March 20, 1863; 228675 (Box 1, Folder S62)
  - Andrews, Israel W., Why is Allegiance Due? And Where is it Due? Address before National Union Association of Cincinnati 30p., June 2, 1863; 228674 (Box 1, Folder S63)
  - Baker, John., The Rebellion: A Speech by Jehu Baker, delivered in the Hall of Representatives, Springfield, Ill., Feb. 4; at Bloomington, March 20; at Belleville, March 28. 32 p., February-March 1863; 228673 (Box 1, Folder S64)
  - The Ballot Box, the Palladium of our Liberties 65p., July 1863; 228672 (Box 1, Folder S65)
  - Bassett, George W., A Northern Plea for the Right of Succession 24p., 1861; 228671 (Box 1, Folder S66)
  - Beasley, Robert E., A Plan to Stop the Present and Prevent Future Wars 24p., 1864; 228670 (Box 1, Folder S67)
  - Blanchard, Charles., Chief Justice Eaton's Seymour Letter, Remarks by Charles Blanchard 12p., April 4 and 11, 1863; 228669 (Box 1, Folder S68)
  - Brent, George Wm. Speech of Geo. Wm. Brent of Alexandria, in the Virginia Convention 16p., March 8, 1861; 228668 (Box 1, Folder S69)
  - Brough, John. Dayton Speech. President Lincoln's Response Relative to the Arrest of Vallandigham 31p., 1863; 228667 (Box 1, Folder S70)
  - Brough, John., The Defenders of the Country and its Enemies. The Chicago Platform Dissected, 16p., September 5, 1864; 228666 (Box 1, Folder S72)
  - Coggeshall, Wm. T., Ohio's Prosperity, Social, and Material; An Argument Against Rebellion, applied to the duty of citizens 8p., 1863?; 228665 (Box 1, Folder S72)
  - Conkling, Henry., An Inside View of the Rebellion, and American Citizen's Textbook 23p., 1864; 228664 (Box 1, Folder S73)
  - The Constitution and the Union Speeches delivered at the Am. Union Breakfast, Paris 24p., May 29, 1861; 228663 (Box 1, Folder S74)
  - Conway, Martin F., Shall the war be for union and freedom or union and slavery? 14p., December 12, 1861; 228662 (Box 1, Folder S75)
  - Drake, Charles D. Speech delivered before the National Union Association 16p., October 1, 1864; 228661 (Box 1, Folder S76)
  - Edgerton, Henry. State of the Union. 20p., February 14, 1861; 228660 (Box 2, Folder S77)
  - Ewing, Thomas. Letter Relative to Charges Against Our Generals who Fought the Battle of Shiloh, 12p., November 1, 1862; 228659 (Box 2, Folder S78)
  - Facts for the People: Relating to the Present Crisis, 16p., July 30, 1862; 228658 (Box 2, Folder S79)
  - Flagg, William J. Speech delivered in Ohio House of Representatives, on the Resolution of Mr. West to expel Hon. Otto Dressel 16p., March 25, 1863; 228657 (Box 2, Folder S80)
  - Freligh, J.H., The True Position, Interests, and Policy of the South. Union or Succession: Which is Best? (in 4 nos.) The Crisis (in 8 nos.) 35p., 1861; 228656 (Box 2, Folder S81)
  - Gantt, E.W. Address of Brigadier-General E.W. Gantt, C.S.A. 29p., October 7, 1863; 228655 (Box 2, Folder S82)
  - Geeup, Jehu., North and South, or What is Slavery? 12p., 1861; 228654 (Box 2, Folder S83)
  - Glover, Samuel T., Slavery in the United States--Emancipation in Missouri. 18p., July 22, 1863; 228653 (Box 2, Folder S84)
  - Hamilton, Andrew Jackson. Addres of A.J. Hamilton, Military Governor to the People of Texas 19p., 1864; 228652 (Box 2, Folder S85)
  - Hamilton, Andrew J. Letter of Gen. A.J. Hamilton, of Texas, to the President of the United States 18p., 1863; 228651 (Box 2, Folder S86)
  - Holt, Joseph., The Fallacy of Neutrality. Address and letter to J.F. Speed, Esq. 31p., July 13, 1861; 228650 (Box 2, Folder S87)
  - Holt, Joseph. Letter Upon the Policy of the General Government, the Pending Revolution, its Objectives, its probable results if successful, and the Duty of Kentucky in the Crisis. 23p., 1861; 228649 (Box 2, Folder S88)
  - Interior Causes of the War: The Nation Demonized and its President a Spirit-Rapper, 115p., 1863; 228648 (Box 2, Folder S89)
  - Johnston, William., An Address on the Aspect of National Affairs and the Right of Sucession, 42p., March 16, 1861; 228647 (Box 2, Folder S90)
  - McDougall, James A. Speech on the Arrest of Gen. Stone, and the Rights of the Soldier and the Citizen 32p., April 15, 16, and 22, 1862; 228646 (Box 2, Folder S91)
  - Maury, M.F. Captain Maury's Letter on American Affairs. Also the Address of Hon. John C. Breckinridge to the People of Kentucky 16p. (also letter from Maury dated Richmond, VA. August 1861), 228645 (Box 2, Folder S92)
  - Morton, Oliver P. Speech at the Union State Convention Held at Indianapolis, Ind. 24p., February 23, 1864; 228644 (Box 2, Folder S93)
  - Neill, Edward D., The Relations of the Government to the Indian Tribes, 4p., January 31, 1863; 228643 (Box 2, Folder S94)
  - New Orleans Picayne Extracts from Editorial Columns 23p., 1861; 228642 (Box 2, Folder S95)
  - Perry, Aaron F. Speech Delivered Before National Union Association at Mozart Hall, Cincinnati 15p., September 20, 1864; 228641 (Box 2, Folder S96)
  - Plumly, B. Rush Speech delivered before the free colored men of New Orleans, Economy Hall 16p., November 14, 1864; 228640 (Box 2, Folder S97)
  - Post, T.M. Palingenesy., National Regeneration, 17p., November 4, 1864; 228639 (Box 2, Folder S98)
  - Price, William, The Position of Maryland. Letter to the Editors of the Baltimore American, 8p., 1861; 228638 (Box 2, Folder S99)
  - Read and Think on This. Address of some Loyal Citizens to Those of their Fellow-Citizens of Harrison County, whom they would have return to loyalty, 5p., 1862?; 228637 (Box 2, Folder S100)
  - Reynolds, Thomas C., Speech of Liet. Gov. Reynolds on the Preservation or Reconstruction of the Union, 9p., January 17, 1861; 228636 (Box 2, Folder S101)
  - Rives, William C., Speech on the Proceedings of the Peace Conference and the State of the Union, 24p., March 8, 1861; 228635 (Box 2, Folder S102)
  - Robb, James A., Southern Confederacy. Letter to Hon. A.H. Stephens of Georgia, 17p., 1863; 228634 (Box 2, Folder S103)
  - Segar, Jos., Letter to Gen. Dix, 9p. Letter dated Washington Nov. 20 1861, 228633 (Box 2, Folder S104)
  - Slocum, Wm. N., The War and How to End It. An Address to the People of California, 38p., November 1861; 228632 (Box 2, Folder S104a)
  - Society of California Pioneers inaugural ceremonies at the opening of the new "Pioneer Hall", 27p., January 8, 1863; 228631 (Box 2, Folder S105)
  - South Carolina, Disunion and a Mississippi Valley Confederacy, 15p., 1861?; 228630 (Box 2, Folder S106)
  - Southern Hatred of the American Government, the People of the North, and Free Institutions, 48p., 1862; 228629 (Box 2, Folder S107)
  - Southern Rights Convention. Address and Resolutions Adopted at the Meeting of the Southern Rights Convention of Maryland, 14p., February 18-19, 1861; 228628 (Box 2, Folder S108)
  - Stanberry, Henry., The Ballot and the Bullet. How to Save the Nation 8p., September 17, 1864; 228627 (Box 2, Folder S109)
  - Stanly, Edward. Letter to Col. Henry A. Gilliam, Refuting Certain Charges and Insinuations made by Hon. Geo. E. Badger in Behalf of the Southern Confederacy, 10p., July 17, 1862; 228626 (Box 2, Folder S110)
  - Stebbins, Horatio, The President, the People, and the War: A Thanksgiving Discourse, 22p., 1864; 228625 (Box 2, Folder S111)
  - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton Prophecy and Fulfillment. Speech in Opposition to Secession 21p. Also bound address of E.W. Gantt in Favor of Re-union in 1863 22p., November 14, 1860; 228624 (Box 2, Folder S112)
  - Sullivan, J.P., The Political Status of Louisiana and the Consequences of Armed Secession. Speech Before the Union Association of New Orleans, 9p., November 28-29, 1863; 228623 (Box 2, Folder S113)
  - Taylor, James W., The Sioux War: What Has Been Done by the Minnesota Campaign of 1863, and what Should be Done During a Dakota Campaign of 1864, 16p., 228622 (Box 2, Folder S114)
  - Union State Central Committee. Address of the Union State Central Committee of Maryland 8p., 1861?; 228621 (Box 2, Folder S115)
  - Vilas, Levi B. Speech before Union mass meetings at Lacrosse and Madison, Wis. 8p., October 1-13, 1862; 228620 (Box 2, Folder S116)
  - Wade, Ben. On McClellan and Gens. Hooker and Heintzelman's Testimony. A Crushing Review of Little Napoleon's Military Career. 8p., 1864?; 228619 (Box 2, Folder S117)
  - Wallis, S. Teackle. Speech Delivered at the Maryland Institute. 15p., February 1, 1861; 228618 (Box 2, Folder S118)
  - Warner, John R., Our Times and Our Duty. An Oration Delivered by Request at Spangler's Grove, Gettysburg, 16p., July 4, 1861; 228617 (Box 2, Folder S119)
  - Willey, Waitman T. Object of the War. Speech in the Senate, 15p., December 19 and 20, 1861; 228616 (Box 2, Folder S120)
  - Willey, Waitman T. Speech on Mr. Moore's Resolutions on Federal Relations in the Virginia Convention 16p., March 4, 1861; 228615 (Box 2, Folder S121)
  - Toledo Blade Annual Statement of the Trade and Commerce of Toledo, for the year 1863 44p., 1864; 228614 (Box 2, Folder S122)
  - The Workman's Monthly Pocket Time-Book, 1864; 228613 (Box 2, Folder S123)
  - Conway, T.W. Report on the Condition of the Freed Men, of the Department of the Gulf, to Major Gen. N.P. Banks 11p., 1864; 228612 (Box 2, Folder S124)
  - Hamlin, C. The Problem of Freedom and Slavery in the United States. Lecture before the Literary and Scientific Institution of Smyrna 28p., March 6, 1862; 228611 (Box 2, Folder S125)
  - Laurens, Henry., A South Carolina Protest Against Slavery: Being a Letter to his Son, Colonel John Laurens, 34p. (August 14, 1776, Original), 1861; 228610 (Box 2, Folder S126)
  - Sargent, F.W., Les Etats Confederes et l'Esclavage par F.W. Sargent de Philadelphie, 177p., 1864; 228609 (Box 2, Folder S127)
  - Thomson, Mortimer., What Became of the Slaves on a Georgia Plantation? Great Auction Sale of Slaves at Savannah, March 2-3 1859. A Sequel to Mrs. Kemble's Journal, 1863, 20p., 1859, 1863; 228608 (Box 2, Folder S128)
  - A Fairy's Failure. Written and Printed for the Devoted Patriots of East Tennessee, 16p., 1864; 228607 (Box 2, Folder S129)
  - The Art of Making Saltpeter, 186-; 228606 (Box 2, Folder S129a)
  - McClellan Campaign Song, 1864?; 228605 (Box 2, Folder S129b)
  - The Nation Mourns, 186-; 228604 (Box 2, Folder S129c)
  - Pike, Albert., Southsons, hear your country call you!, 186-; 228603 (Box 2, Folder S129d)
  - Randall, James Ryder., There's Life in the Old Land Yet!, 186-; 228602 (Box 2, Folder S129e)
  - Upham, Louise S., The Nation is Weeping, 186-; 228601 (Box 2, Folder S129f)
  - Haven, Erastus O., Universities in America. Inaugural Address as President of Univ. of Michigan, 31p., October 1, 1863; 228600 (Box 2, Folder S130)
  - Mayo, A.D., The Scholar's Vocation in the New Republic. Address before Union Literary Society of Antioch College 28p., June 30, 1863; 228599 (Box 2, Folder S131)
  - Bassett, Geo. W., A Discourse on the Wickedness and Folly of the Present War, 24p., August 11, 1861; 228598 (Box 2, Folder S132)
  - Cummins, George D., The African a Trust from God to the American. A sermon delivered on the day of National Humiliation, Fasting, and Prayer in St. Peter's Church, Baltimore, 28p., January 4, 1861; 228597 (Box 2, Folder S133)
  - Eliot, William G., Emancipation in Missouri, 8p., July 5, 1863; 228596 (Box 2, Folder S134)
  - Eliot, William G., Loyalty and Religion, 12p., August 18, 1861; 228595 (Box 2, Folder S135)
  - Fairfield, Edmund B. Christian Patriotism. Sermon delivered in Representatives' Hall, Lansing, Mich. 40p., February 22, 1863; 228594 (Box 2, Folder S136)